liveuamap.com 2019-03-31

# Liveuamap Company

### About

Live Universal Awareness Map (“Liveuamap”) is a leading independent global news and information site dedicated to factual reporting of a variety of important topics including conflicts, human rights issues, protests, terrorism, weapons deployment, health matters, natural disasters, and weather related stories, among others, from a vast array of sources. We are passionate about what we do and are energized by the positive impact we bring, as demonstrated by the loyalty and recommendations of our growing viewers across the globe. 

Our innovative map-centric approach to organization of information will allow our viewers to quickly find the stories most relevant to them, and in geographies of their interest. We provide open online access to a complete chronological archive of our site information, enabling the viewers to research past events and historical trends. We aspire to be the authoritative reference for the news and topics we cover by bringing clarity and transparency of information demanded by our viewers across the world. As dedicated and impartial reporters we consider ourselves citizens of the greater world, independent of geographic and political bias. Using our big data analysis methods, we aim to help predict and prevent future conflicts, minimize the impact of disasters, and assist travelers around the world in making conscious decisions about their security throughout their journeys. 

At Liveuamap we use proprietary software tools, such as its AI web crawlers, to find news-worthy stories which will be forwarded to our group of expert analysts for fact checking. Our dedicated editors decide which facts and stories should be displayed on the map to minimize spam. Our software development team is working on future improvements which will enable our viewers to create and manage their own maps. 

Liveuamap was founded in 2014 by a team of devoted software developers and journalists who wished to inform the world about the Ukrainian conflict. By viewer request, it quickly expanded its scope to cover other regions, including Syria, Israel-Palestine and "Islamic State war" news. Today, it cover more than 30 regions and topics, offers translations in several languages and can be used on mobile browsers via its own Apps which can be downloaded from Apple App Store for iOS or Google Play Market for Android. 

Liveuamap operates from its EU-based technical infrastructure and is governed by Liveuamap LLC under the jurisdiction of the State of Virginia, USA. 

Liveuamap main revenue source is advertising. We are using open advertising platforms, and not influence the advertising showing at platform. Most advertising platforms using cookies(see Privacy) to decide what to show you 

As advertising revenues across media are falling fast, we offer every our user to contribute to our project and buy Liveuamap PRO subscription at [/me.liveuamap.com/welcome](https://me.liveuamap.com/welcome). Liveuamap PRO offers Advertising-free experience, also as Satellite maps 

We offer enterprises to use our API and other Enterprise services(as advanced social media data mining and analysis for defined areas). Liveuamap API allows to integrate our data into existing solutions or build new software over it 

CONTRIBUTE

If you know or find some information that worth to be added to the map, have some feedback on website and applications send it to info@liveuamap.com  

### Privacy

Thank you for visiting this website, a digital service presented to you by Liveuamap LLC ("Liveuamap", "we" or "us"). Your privacy is important to us. As such, we provide this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used by us, which includes our online or mobile websites and applications through which this Privacy Policy appears (each a "Service," collectively the "Services"). "Users" are persons that use the Services.

**The Information We Collect and Store**

If you are not loggged-in with our website, we do not store any personal information, otherwise we store only information that could help us identify you as a certain user: Name, Facebook or Twitter Id's, E-mail address and Password. For billing purposes we are storing your payment history.

**Personal information in the stories**

All our stories were gathered from open sources, if you are subject to the story, but there are legal reasons to not your private data, contact us and we will remove any information as soon as possible.

**The Information We Collect**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here (<https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>). 

### Mobile applications privacy

Android and iOS Application, are digital services presented to you by Liveuamap LLC ("Liveuamap", "we" or "us"). Your privacy is important to us. As such, we provide Mobile applications privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used by us, which includes our mobile applications through which this Privacy Policy appears (each a "Service," collectively the "Services"). "Users" are persons that use the Services. 

**Privacy of advertising**  
Liveuamap is using AdMob mobile application advertising platform created by Google. It’s used to promote mobile apps and to help advertisers make money through mobile apps by enabling in-app advertising. AdMob also works with Google Analytics to help us get insight and information about Liveuamap app’s usage and the effectiveness of any advertising campaigns. To use this service we have to collect and transmit the Android advertising identifier.   
**Other 3rd party services**  
For notifications we are using onesignal.com service, that gathering information necessary for targeted notification service. Particularly settings inside application(region, language and geolocation. Geolocation transmitted only when you tap "geolocate me" element inside map or selecting location manually, the last location transmitted by your action considered as location to send notifications ). Onesignal stores ID of every application installed, allowing to identify your Device.   
**Analytics and Crash reports**  
We are using Google Firebase mobile and web application development platform. Firebase Analytics allow us to get insight and information about Liveuamap app’s usage, identify device, it's country, Demography, actions inside application(like session start) 

**The Information We Collect and Store** If you are not loggged-in with our application, we do not store any personal information, otherwise we store only information that could help us identify you as a certain user: E-mail address and Password. For billing purposes we are storing your payment history. 

**Personal information in the stories** All our stories were gathered from open sources, if you are subject to the story, but there are legal reasons to not show your private data, contact us and we will remove any information as soon as possible. 

### Cookies

**What are cookies?**

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are sent to your browser and stored on your computer, mobile phone or other device when you visit a website. The cookies send information back to the originating website or another website that recognizes that cookie.

Cookies can be permanent (these are known as persistent cookies) where they remain on your computer until you delete them, or temporary (these are known as session cookies) where they last only until you close your browser. Cookies can also be first-party cookies which are those set by the website which is being visited, or third-party cookies which are set by a website other than the one being visited. 

**How does Liveuamap use cookies?**

We use cookies to personalize your experience at our site, e.g. to save your language, save your password in password-protected areas. Also cookies are used by our Advertising Systems(3rd parties) 

### Terms

These Terms of Service (“Terms”) govern your access to and use of our services, including our various websites, maps, APIs, email notifications, applications, and our other covered services, and any information, text, links, graphics, photos, videos, or other materials or arrangements of materials uploaded, downloaded or appearing on the Services (collectively referred to as “Content”). By using the Services you agree to be bound by these Terms.

**Who may use the Services**

You may use the Services only if you agree to form a binding contract with Liveuamap and are not a person barred from receiving services under the laws of the applicable jurisdiction. In any case, you must be at least 16 years old to use the Services. If you are accepting these Terms and using the Services on behalf of a company, organization, government, or other legal entity, you represent and warrant that you are authorized to do so. 

You may use our data and maps, including map tiles and areas polygons partially, or in the whole in your work, with reference to liveuamap.com. Images and texts from 3rd party social networks are distibuted under Terms of Service of original resources, that you may access via "source" link. 

Any use or reliance on any Content or materials posted via the Services or obtained by you through the Services is at your own risk. We do not endorse, support, represent of any Content or communications posted via the Services or endorse any opinions expressed via the Services. You understand that by using the Services, you may be exposed to Content that might be offensive, harmful, inaccurate or otherwise inappropriate. All Content is the sole responsibility of the person who originated such Content. 

**Privacy**

Our Privacy Policy [(https://liveuamap.com/about#privacy)](https://liveuamap.com/about#privacy) describes how we handle the information you provide to us when you use our Services.
